<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>words</title>
 <link href="http://hcorona.github.io/words/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://hcorona.github.io/words/"/>
 <updated>2015-10-26T16:36:35+00:00</updated>
 <id>http://hcorona.github.io/words</id>
 <author>
   <name>Humberto Corona</name>
   <email></email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>si, soy vegetariano</title>
   <link href="http://hcorona.github.io/words/govegan/"/>
   <updated>2015-10-16T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://hcorona.github.io/words/govegan</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Muchísimas veces mis amigos, familia, o simples desconocidos me han preguntado ¿Por qué soy vegetariano? La respuesta corta es porque si!, la respuesta larga está aquí.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No os voy a contar la típica historia de mi colesterol, el médico que me asusta y todo ese rollo. Es un poco aburrida y sinceramente, no refleja toda la profundidad de este tema.  El rollo de perdí peso, me siento con mas energía y mi piel es maravillosa es un poco repetitivo, aunque si es cierto que mi piel es maravillosa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Creo que la mayoría de tenemos miedo al cambio. Nos parece una locura que otro modelo económico pueda funcionar o que dos hombres puedan estar “casados”. Nos aferramos a todas nuestras tradiciones, a las cosas que nos definen como sociedad, algunas buenas, otras malas. Seguimos haciendo cosas que detestamos  porque “es lo que hay que hacer” aunque nos hagan pasar por un dolor innecesario. Por eso, para muchos, conocer a un vegetariano es de lo mas punk; un bicho raro que causa curiosidad al que no acabamos de entender.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Siempre me he preguntado el por qué de las cosas que afectan a mi vida. Cual es el sentido de llevar un traje al trabajo? Por qué he de tratar a alguien de forma especial? Cual es el problema de llevar el pelo rojo al primer día del cole cuando tienes 13? Me he metido en bastante problemas por ser cabezón, pero sobretodo por defender lo que creo. Bueno, tampoco voy a exagerar, no soy un activista ni nada parecido. La última vez que fui a una manifestación fue en la guerra de Irak.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pienso, o mejor dicho, se que comer productos animales es malo para el planeta, muy malo, fatal para el planeta! El gobierno te dice que comas carne porque si no tendría a un montón de gente (agricultores, ganaderos, etc.) en contra; gente que gasta bastante dinero en lobbying  a la cual mejor mantener tranquila.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vivimos en un planeta con recursos limitados, pero nuestro modelo de vivir se basa en un crecimiento ilimitado. Es decir, cada vez nuestra economía produce mas, tenemos mas hijos, comemos más, y compramos un montón mas. Este modelo no funciona. Todos lo sabemos, pero todos nos olvidamos y preferimos ver el nuevo episodio de &lt;em&gt;The Greatest British Bakeoff&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Os voy a dar un par de cifras. La producción de carne ocupa el 70% del suelo destinado para la agricultura y el 30% de la superficie del planeta. La expansión de la ganadería es un factor clave en la deforestación, especialmente en el amazonas! Además, la ganadería produce el 18% de los gases de efector hibernado. Mas que toda la industria global del transporte!  – conducir un tesla super guai no va a cambiar mucho el planeta, pero tu vas a molar un montón mas asi que compratelo!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Uno de nuestros recursos mas preciados es el agua. El 8% del agua de consumo humano va a parar al sector de la ganadería, la mayoría para regar cosechas que luego son usadas para alimentar al ganado, y peor aun, probablemente es es la principal causa única de contaminación del agua (y no las compañias petroleras). Piensalo, todas las vacas haciendo cacola que va a parar a nuestros mares sin ser tratadas, los antibióticos que les damos, el amoníaco de su pis, el gas metano que producen, toda la gasolina que los tractores usan para cultivar y cuidar la cosecha de granos que en su mayoría va destinada a la producción de carne. :(&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Para producir un kilo de carne (de vaca) se necesitan sobre 17 mil litros de agua, un kilo de tomates usa 214 litros de agua (80 veces menos que para un Kg de carne de vaca).  Un Kg de tofu necesita 2000 litros y uno de arroz  2500 litros. (puedes leer más &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theguardian.com/news/datablog/2013/jan/10/how-much-water-food-production-waste&quot;&gt;aqui&lt;/a&gt;) – las vacas beben mucho y el proceso de criarlas, matarlas, cortarlas en pedazos y comerlas no es muy eficiente.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Total, que comiendo una hamburguesa estas deforestando el amazonas y consumes la misma cantidad de agua que usas en ducharte 1 mes. Y el gobierno diciéndonos que no reguemos nuestros jardines, estáis de broma?!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Creo que lo ideal sería tener una dieta casi-vegana, por qué no he hecho?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;El principal problema es la gente. Si, la gente. Es un rollo tener que explicarle a alguien a quien apenas conoces el por qué de tus decisiones alimenticias. Me he sentido discriminado e insultado un montón de veces en cenas de galas, conferencias o en restaurantes.  Además, cuestionar mis decisiones de vida no es un tema agradable de conversación si no me conoces y me hace sentir bastante incómodo. &lt;strong&gt;Simplemente no es educado preguntarle a alguien vegetariano que no conoces de donde saca las proteinas. No lo hagas. Nunca! es poco cool! &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Otra cosa es que comprar vegano es un rollo. Vamos a ver, el mundo no se va a acabar porque yo me compre un Naan que lleva yogurt, o unos polvorones no vegetarianos. El privarme de esas cosas me haría acabar siendo un gruñón y no quiero eso.  Además, no voy a leer la etiqueta de todo lo que como porque tengo cosas mejores que hacer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;En resumen, si dejásemos de productos animales el mundo sería un lugar mejor, la deforestación pararía en gran parte, los mares se recuperarían y tu tendrías una piel maravillosa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ahora ya sabes cuales son mis argumentos para ser vegetariano y comer muy pocos productos animales (o ser casi vegano), pero no me juzgues si algún día me ves con una chaqueta de cuero o como gominolas. No tengo por qué ser coherente en todos los aspectos de mi vida, simplemente tengo que ser feliz.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>On references, change and standardisation</title>
   <link href="http://hcorona.github.io/words/on-references-change-and-standardisation/"/>
   <updated>2015-09-28T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://hcorona.github.io/words/on-references-change-and-standardisation</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In the last week I wasted half a day fixing citations for a journal paper. HALF-A-DAY that I could have spent doing actual research! Here is what we should do about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The way we write and use references should change. Drastically. Several standards have been popping in and out for more than 100 years (the Chicago style dates 1906) … there was no internet, telephone or commercial planes back then! This was when you mailed your scientific papers to your colleagues so they could read it. This was when you received copies of journals by the mail. Oops, we still do, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the last 100 years things have changed. In the last 20 years things have changed. In the last 2 years things have probably changed more than in the previous 20! Yet we, people who do research, still use the same format for citations. To me, it makes no sense! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, there is all the fields for a reference. Authors, title of the paper, title of the conference (or journal), volume, edition, pages, publisher etc… When was the last time you searched through an actual book of proceedings to find a paper and found the paper you were looking for in pages 34-46? NEVER! If I can not google it, chances are I will not be reading that paper. I use google scholar to search for papers, and I read and annotate papers on my iPad. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wouldn’t it make more sense to have a reference that includes authors, title of the paper and a unique identifier for it, which would also serve as a URL (DOI, arxiv, are good examples). That url would also serve as a metadata source for the reference. Therefore, the tedious job of fixing typos on the references would be gone! Plus you can just click on it and go to the next paper … easy, right? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then there is the problem of standardisation. Who needs 30 different styles for citations! Dear people who edit conferences and journal proceedings, my life would be easier if there were only 2,3, or even 5 (if you really need them) styles that are very well known, and that’s it! I personally like numbers, but I get other styles such as [name, year] are very elegant, but no one cares if you use a comma or a period as separators, if you have quotations in the title of the paper, if you have the year before or after the title … because 90% of the time I just need the title to google it! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we standardise the formatting to 2 styles (one column, two columns) we can all focus on the content, and leave aside other things. It would also be easier to scan thought papers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What about the tools we use? Last week my friend was copy-pasting references into a .bib file manually, like it was 1995! And to be honest, sometimes I also need to do it because there is no other way around it. I know Mendeley helped a lot there, but we are nowhere close to where we should be. The metadata (that I find completely useless unless I am writing a paper and need to include it) is never correct, and you often need to fix it – a job that no one likes, a waste of time. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having less complex citation styles and heavily standardising them would only lead to less time spent on that and more on the actual problems we want to solve. I would also lead to a lot of new tools built upon that. Imagine how easy would it be to find citations if there was a unique url on the actual paper. Avoid duplicates, better citation counts, easier cross-references, higher availability of the content… the opportunities are endless! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How do I make this happen?&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>HOME/SICK launch @ SCIENCE GALLERY</title>
   <link href="http://hcorona.github.io/words/homesick-science-gallery/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-07T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://hcorona.github.io/words/homesick-science-gallery</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_490&quot; style=&quot;width: 710px&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;http://aloneindecember.com/words/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/IMG_1684.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-490 size-large&quot; src=&quot;http://aloneindecember.com/words/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/IMG_1684-1024x769.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;IMG_1684&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;526&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  
  &lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;
    All the pieces of the exhibition
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week I attended  to the launch of Science Gallery’s new exhibition, entitled  “HOME\SICK post domestic bliss”. Regulars from the Science Gallery events gathered to get the first view on this exhibition;  good music, nice atmosphere and a great exhibition that won’t dissapoint anyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HOME\SICK  “explores how our homes might be reconfigured and reimagined as centres of connection in spite of emigration, of intimacy in spite of digital distraction, of food and energy production rather than consumption”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_492&quot; style=&quot;width: 710px&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;http://aloneindecember.com/words/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/IMG_1674.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-492 size-large&quot; src=&quot;http://aloneindecember.com/words/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/IMG_1674-887x1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;IMG_1674&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;808&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  
  &lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;
    &amp;#8211;
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_489&quot; style=&quot;width: 710px&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;http://aloneindecember.com/words/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/IMG_1681-2.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-489 size-large&quot; src=&quot;http://aloneindecember.com/words/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/IMG_1681-2-1024x636.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;IMG_1681 2&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;435&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  
  &lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;
    &amp;#8211;
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was very interesting to see how the exhibition explores the concept of a home, what constitutes and what surrounds it and builds it. From the alergens and patogens that we find at home, to tools to make home a much better livable space, to stories of people’s home, and even a lighthouse! My favourite was a series of pieces that explore the concept of home for people who, like me, are regularly away from home, or from the people they consider home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_491&quot; style=&quot;width: 710px&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;http://aloneindecember.com/words/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/IMG_1686.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-large wp-image-491&quot; src=&quot;http://aloneindecember.com/words/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/IMG_1686-948x1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;HOME\SICK is open from until 19th of June&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;756&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  
  &lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;
    HOME\SICK is open from until 19th of June
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>LIFELOGGING launch party</title>
   <link href="http://hcorona.github.io/words/lifelogging-launch-party/"/>
   <updated>2015-03-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://hcorona.github.io/words/lifelogging-launch-party</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Last Thursday I attended the launch party for the &lt;a href=&quot;https://dublin.sciencegallery.com&quot;&gt;Science Gallery’s&lt;/a&gt; upcoming exhibition entitled &lt;a href=&quot;https://dublin.sciencegallery.com/lifelogging&quot;&gt;#LIFELOGGING.&lt;/a&gt;   Let me first put this into context. The science gallery is one of my favourite museums in the world, and definetly one of my favourite places in Dublin. It manages to put together great show s where art and science not only mix, but fades together for three months. A truly collaborative enriching experience for both disciplines. This exhibition is my favourite so far, and I wrote about it for my friends at &lt;a href=&quot;http://theissuemagazine.com&quot;&gt;THE ISSUE&lt;/a&gt;. Read the full entry on their website!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_455&quot; style=&quot;width: 710px&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;http://aloneindecember.com/words/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/2015-02-12-18.49.21.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-455 size-large&quot; src=&quot;http://aloneindecember.com/words/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/2015-02-12-18.49.21-768x1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2015-02-12 18.49.21&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;933&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  
  &lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;
    #LIFELOGGING opened February 13th and will be running until April 17th.
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>recsys challenge : part III</title>
   <link href="http://hcorona.github.io/words/recsys-challenge-part-iii/"/>
   <updated>2015-02-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://hcorona.github.io/words/recsys-challenge-part-iii</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In the last two posts about the recsys challenge  (&lt;a href=&quot;http://aloneindecember.com/words/recsys-challenge-part-i/&quot;&gt;part&lt;/a&gt; I and &lt;a href=&quot;http://aloneindecember.com/words/recsys-challenge-part-ii/&quot;&gt;part II&lt;/a&gt;) I have discussed in detail some aspects of this year’s challenge data. This time I present an analysis of the data from the point of view of categories and the role they play in clicks, sessions and buys.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
  Users seem to find items searching for brands,categories, or pushed by sales in the platform!
&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gWcYOz2fpMk&quot;&gt;First things firsts&lt;/a&gt;, we have 52K items distributed in 339 categories. However, clicks are not equally distributed across these categories, and nor are the items. As we expect, both follow a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.longtail.com/about.html&quot;&gt;long tail&lt;/a&gt; distribution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s take a closer look at items and clicks. &lt;em&gt;Which category gets the most number of clicks? What categories gets a higher number of purchases?&lt;/em&gt;  The figure below shows the distribution of clicks across categories. The horizontal axis shows all the categories in the dataset (sorted by number of clicks)  and the vertical axis shows the number of clicks per each category in a logarithmic scale. Thus, we know that there are a very limited number of categories that get most of the clicks (around 50), while the remainder 250 or so get a very limited number of clicks.  Worth mentioning that the decay of the distribution is very steep, like the Cliffs of Moher (as seen in my &lt;a href=&quot;http://diary.aloneindecember.com/post/91981935551&quot;&gt;visual diary&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_427&quot; style=&quot;width: 710px&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;http://aloneindecember.com/words/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cat_pop_clicks.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-large wp-image-427&quot; src=&quot;http://aloneindecember.com/words/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cat_pop_clicks-1024x613.png&quot; alt=&quot;The distribution of categories across clicks follows a long tail distribution&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;419&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  
  &lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;
    The distribution of categories across clicks follows a long tail distribution
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s take a closer look at the distribution. The figure below focuses on the top 10 categories, sorted by number of clicks. Together, all the items from the category ‘0’ where clicked 16337653 times, which is 155 times more clicks than for category ‘9’, in which users clicked 105282 times. In fact, the first 10 categories shown below account for 99% of all clicks in the dataset. Leaving the remainder 299 categories with only 1% of the clicks, very uninteresting items seems to be …&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides the distribution, something that strikes me is why is there an &lt;span style=&quot;color: #ff99cc;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‘S’&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt; category, when all the other categories are encoded with numbers? Does it has an special meaning? Comments section is open if you have an answer or theory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_432&quot; style=&quot;width: 710px&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;http://aloneindecember.com/words/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cat_pop_clicks_top2.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-432 size-large&quot; src=&quot;http://aloneindecember.com/words/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cat_pop_clicks_top2-1024x613.png&quot; alt=&quot;cat_pop_clicks_top&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;419&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  
  &lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;
    Distribution of clicks for the top 10 most clicked categories
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now we can compare the graph above  with the one below, obtained from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.walkersands.com/futureofretail&quot;&gt;Walker Sands’ 2014 future of retail study&lt;/a&gt;.We could asume, or figure out that the categories are also organised as below. Dreaming or imagining is free, so why not? Anyway, that doesn’t tells much. If we knew what type of categories get more buys and that was different to the clicks they get, that would be intresting, right? &lt;strong&gt;#moredataplease &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_440&quot; style=&quot;width: 310px&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;http://aloneindecember.com/words/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/Screen-Shot-2015-02-01-at-17.32.01.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-440 size-medium&quot; src=&quot;http://aloneindecember.com/words/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/Screen-Shot-2015-02-01-at-17.32.01-300x214.png&quot; alt=&quot;The categories of products most bought online&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;214&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  
  &lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;
    The categories of products most bought online
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know have more questions than when I started. For example,* is the distribution of categories across items the same as across clicks? Do categories get more clicks because those categories have more items?* &lt;strong&gt;NO!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The graph below shows the top 10 categories sorted by number of items. The vertical axis shows each category with it’s id, sorted by the category size, while the vertical item represents the number of items in a logarithmic scale.  We see some of the categories from the graph above, while some new categories come in, showing that not all the categories with a large number of items necessarily get a large number of clicks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_434&quot; style=&quot;width: 710px&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;http://aloneindecember.com/words/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cat_items1.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-large wp-image-434&quot; src=&quot;http://aloneindecember.com/words/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cat_items1-1024x613.png&quot; alt=&quot;Distribution of categories across items&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;419&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  
  &lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;
    Distribution of categories across items
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far so good, all pretty boring until here … except for the magic “S” and the category “0”. The way the data is presented, we could assume that each item belongs to only one category. However, the figure below shows that this is not the case. Some items appear in our click data with more than one category in different transactions, now that is something I didn’t expect…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_437&quot; style=&quot;width: 710px&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;http://aloneindecember.com/words/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/correlation2.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-437 size-large&quot; src=&quot;http://aloneindecember.com/words/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/correlation2-1024x613.png&quot; alt=&quot;correlation&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;419&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  
  &lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;
    Correlation between categories
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The figure above shows the number of shared items among the biggest categories (transformed by a logarithm for better visualisation). The first thing we see is that the category ‘0’ is highly correlated to all the other ones, the same goes for category ‘S’. My assumption here is that those categories are used as ‘&lt;em&gt;default&lt;/em&gt;‘ or ‘&lt;em&gt;none&lt;/em&gt;‘, and at some point they are replaced by a better indicator of the category, or simply those are categories which apply to almost every item.  Either ways, it is something to bare in mind when building the models to predict purchases&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can see from the graph above that category ‘0’ is highly correlated to most of the other top 10 cateories. But that is not the case for most of them (except ‘S’ which is also correlated to most of the others). My assumption is that category 0 just means no category, and category S means something similar . However, we know that the data is dynamic, so the products might be unlabeled and then labeled, or mislabeled, and then unlabeled … the magic of real world data?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, we can analyse the categories and sessions together, with the hope to find more answers, and even more questions. &lt;em&gt;Do people tend to click in many categories, do they browse mostly in one category?&lt;/em&gt; The graph below shows that users tend to browse within one category.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_439&quot; style=&quot;width: 710px&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;http://aloneindecember.com/words/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cat_sessions.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-439 size-large&quot; src=&quot;http://aloneindecember.com/words/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cat_sessions-1024x613.png&quot; alt=&quot;cat_sessions&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;419&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  
  &lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;
    In a typical session, the user browses though only one or two categories
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the typical scenario, where you are looking to buy the latest Lena Dunham book, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.co.uk/Not-That-Kind-Girl-Learned/dp/0008101264/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1422988023&amp;amp;sr=8-1&amp;amp;keywords=lenna+dunham&quot;&gt;I’m not that kind of girl&lt;/a&gt; (highly recommendable one by the way) and you get lost browsing though thousands of similar books such as Tavi Gevison’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.co.uk/s/ref=a9_sc_1?rh=i%3Aaps%2Ck%3Arookie+yearbook&amp;amp;keywords=rookie+yearbook&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1422988039&quot;&gt;Rookie yearbook&lt;/a&gt;. However, in the same session you wouldn’t probably search for a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.co.uk/Kitchen-Craft-KCBANSLICE-Banana-Slicer/dp/B003CLFC98/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1422988086&amp;amp;sr=8-1&amp;amp;keywords=banana+slicer&quot;&gt;Banana slicer&lt;/a&gt; (a very popular and mediocre item in amazon with hilarious reviews)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;As you might have figured out already, I don’t answer all the questions I propose.&lt;/strong&gt; Some of them will be left for future posts, some of them are food for thought. Download the data, do the analysis and share it!  Finally,  I would like to thank the members of the  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.insight-centre.org/about/team&quot;&gt;recommender systems team&lt;/a&gt; in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.insight-centre.org&quot;&gt;Insight Centre for Data Analytics&lt;/a&gt; for their discussions on this topic. Some of the figures here were first shown to me by them.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>recsys challenge: part II</title>
   <link href="http://hcorona.github.io/words/recsys-challenge-part-ii/"/>
   <updated>2015-01-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://hcorona.github.io/words/recsys-challenge-part-ii</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;After my first entry on the recsys challenge (&lt;a href=&quot;http://aloneindecember.com/words/recsys-challenge-part-i/&quot;&gt;recsys challenge: part I&lt;/a&gt;) , I now show analyse some time patterns more in depth. It is important to understand &lt;strong&gt;when do people browse and buy?&lt;/strong&gt;, to include that information in our model (if that turns out to be valuable)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
  When do people buy stuff?&lt;br /&gt; Well, definitely not Tuesdays!
&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To answer the question, I will follow a top down approach, from moths to days to hours, trying to understand how people behave in the scenario presented by this dataset. I will also compare the trends found here with those found in the previous recsys challenges, finding that user behaviour is, as one can expect, domain dependent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Lets analyse the monthly trends.&lt;/em&gt; The figure below shows a histogram of the number of transactions per month. We show both purchases (blue line, left vertical axis) and clicks (green line, right vertical axis). As we know from the previous post, we are given six months worth of data – April to September 2014. There are two main things to highlight from this graph: First, the activity on the site was decreasing from April to July, with the browsing activity decreasing at a lower pace than the buying activity, being the global maximum located in July (beware the different scales in the graph, even in July, there are many more clicks than purchases). In August the activity of the site reaches it maximum value. &lt;strong&gt;This effect might have something to do with summer sales, so maybe this e-commerce  platform sells seasonal items such as clothes. &lt;/strong&gt;Moreover, the conversion rate (fraction of number of purchases per click) in the second quarter (July, August and September) is  higher than for the first quarter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_422&quot; style=&quot;width: 1010px&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;http://aloneindecember.com/words/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/month_hist1.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-422 size-full&quot; src=&quot;http://aloneindecember.com/words/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/month_hist1.png&quot; alt=&quot;month_hist&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  
  &lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;
    Site activity, monthly histogram
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, I am assuming we are given all there data there is. I also assume there is no other artefact or filtering on the data we are given that could bias the data, something which is not certain (might have to ask @recsyschallenge). &lt;strong&gt;However, given these assumptions are true, the data could be showing us an interesting behaviour on the way people buy things, holding off from buying in June, knowing that they can find the same product cheaper in July&lt;/strong&gt;. It would be interesting to see what are the figures like per category (something left for the next blog post in a few weeks).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Let’s now analyse the daily pattern per month.&lt;/em&gt; This is very interesting, as it can help us understand, for example, &lt;strong&gt;what day do people buy things, in relation to when they get paid?&lt;/strong&gt;. The figure below show a histogram of the site activity, where time has been divided by dates, from the first to the last day of each month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;line-height: 1.5;&quot;&gt;To be honest, I would expect to see a different result, maybe we need more data to see that people tend to spend their paycheques as soon as possible, but the data tells us that the site has more activity on week 2 and 3 of the month. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;line-height: 1.5;&quot;&gt;However, there is an interesting trend show in the graph. The distance between each peak of activity (this is, the wavelength) is exactly 4 days, except for the period 13th – 18th, which lasts 6 days instead of 4. For now, I leave this as an open question, the comments section is open for answers.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_386&quot; style=&quot;width: 1010px&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-386 size-full&quot; src=&quot;http://aloneindecember.com/words/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/day_month.png&quot; alt=&quot;day_month&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; /&gt;
  
  &lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;
    Site activity, date histogram
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;So lets now see the day of the week&lt;/em&gt;. This is extremely interesting, and generated some discussion in my &lt;a href=&quot;http://insight-centre.org/content/recommender-systems&quot;&gt;group&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;strong&gt;It turns out the site has its highest activity is on Sundays&lt;/strong&gt;, followed by Mondays. This is somehow expected if we hypothesise people do not work on Sundays, and in many countries in Europe (specially in smaller cities) shops are closed that day. People are terrified of spending a whole day without buying something, so they buy things online. However, the minimum activity found on Tuesdays is harder to explain (again, comments section are open). The rest of the week shows a more stable daily activity of circa 150K to 180k purchases/day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_387&quot; style=&quot;width: 1010px&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-387 size-full&quot; src=&quot;http://aloneindecember.com/words/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/day_of_week.png&quot; alt=&quot;day_of_week&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; /&gt;
  
  &lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;
    Site activity, day histogram
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Let’s now take a look at the data on an hourly basis&lt;/em&gt;, which also shows some interesting trends. The figure below shows a histogram of purchases and clicks on an hourly basis for all the data. Of course, when people are sleeping they do not buy things (not yet). However, &lt;strong&gt;as the sun rises, the activity does too, reaching a peak of activity of both sales and purchases at 9am, presumably when people arrive to work.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Later again the activity increases after lunch and reaches the daily maximum value at 20h, just after european time for dinner.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_388&quot; style=&quot;width: 1010px&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-388 size-full&quot; src=&quot;http://aloneindecember.com/words/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/hour.png&quot; alt=&quot;hour&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; /&gt;
  
  &lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;
    Site activity, hour histogram
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, online activity and traffic is domain dependent, and @alansaid was kind enough to point me to a paper that contains the graph shown below. It was published as part of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://recsys.acm.org/recsys13/nrs/&quot;&gt;News Recommender Systems Challenge in RecSys’13&lt;/a&gt;. Here, the average number of impressions received (a metric correlated to the number of articles being read) shows a different pattern. **If we take a look at the yellow and orange line (both coming from newspapers) the peak reaches at around lunchtime. **Thus, people start the day buying or browsing for a while, work until lunch time, and when they are back from lunch, they read the newspaper before starting again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_396&quot; style=&quot;width: 710px&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-396 size-large&quot; src=&quot;http://aloneindecember.com/words/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/Screen-Shot-2015-01-09-at-13.57.59-1024x686.png&quot; alt=&quot;Avg impressions per hour (per publisher)&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;469&quot; /&gt;
  
  &lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;
    Average number of impressions histogram, on an hourly basis. Figure taken from the paper: Said, A., Lin, J., Bellogín, A., &amp;amp; de Vries, A. (2013, November). A month in the life of a production news recommender system. In Proceedings of the 2013 workshop on Living labs for information retrieval evaluation (pp. 7-10). ACM.
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope some of you are familiar with the &lt;a href=&quot;http://recsys.acm.org/recsys14/challenge-workshop/&quot;&gt;Recsys’14 challenge&lt;/a&gt;, it used the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sidooms/MovieTweetings&quot;&gt;MovieTweetings&lt;/a&gt; dataset which contains information about users tweeting ratings for IMDB movies. Again, I got the figures for the hourly activity to show the full picture of activities in different challenges in the RecSys conferences through the years.  The figure below shows that &lt;strong&gt;people tend to post these tweets about movies late night, that is when most of people have time to watch movies I guess&lt;/strong&gt;. However, the activity at 5h is very similar than 16h (good question would be if the data shows local time or UTC time?)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_401&quot; style=&quot;width: 570px&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-401 size-full&quot; src=&quot;http://aloneindecember.com/words/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/tweets-imdb.png&quot; alt=&quot;tweets-imdb&quot; width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;420&quot; /&gt;
  
  &lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;
    Activity histogram from the MovieTweetings dataset, hourly based
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
  Side note!, this data tells us that people wake up, buy things, work, read the news paper, go home,  buy things and watch movies, only to wake up, buy things, work, read the news papers, go home, buy more things and watch movies&amp;#8230;
&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Going back to this year’s challenge, We know that, days and hours are not independent. An average person’s schedule on Monday is not the same as Saturday and Sunday, as ur weeks are usually divided into weeks and weekends (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phdcomics.com/comics/archive.php?comicid=453&quot;&gt;unless you are a PhD student&lt;/a&gt;). The graphs below show the histogram of activity in the site where a week is divided into 169 slots of length 1 hour (horizontal axis). Once the data is analysed like in this way, further trends seem to arise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_399&quot; style=&quot;width: 1272px&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-399 size-full&quot; src=&quot;http://aloneindecember.com/words/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/168hours_pattern.png&quot; alt=&quot;168hours_pattern&quot; width=&quot;1262&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; /&gt;
  
  &lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;
    Site activity, weekly histogram (divided by hours)
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The most interesting pattern seen here, besides the fact that people wake up later on weekends, is how the conversion rate (number purchases per clicks) varies with time.&lt;/strong&gt; Not surprisingly, the highest conversion rates are found in Saturday and Sunday, which tells us that people have more free time on weekends, and are more free (or bored) to make decisions or buy things, tons and tons of things. Again, Tuesdays seem odd, very little browsing, and even less purchasing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_398&quot; style=&quot;width: 934px&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-398 size-full&quot; src=&quot;http://aloneindecember.com/words/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/buysperclick.png&quot; alt=&quot;buysperclick&quot; width=&quot;924&quot; height=&quot;420&quot; /&gt;
  
  &lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;
    Site conversion rate, weekly histogram (divided by hours)
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the end of the second entry. Hope to publish a third entry soon with more insights on the data that will help me build a model. I would like to thank the members of the  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.insight-centre.org/about/team&quot;&gt;recommender systems team&lt;/a&gt; in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.insight-centre.org/&quot;&gt;Insight Centre for Data Analytics&lt;/a&gt; for their discussions on this topic.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>recsys challenge: part I</title>
   <link href="http://hcorona.github.io/words/recsys-challenge-part-i/"/>
   <updated>2015-01-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://hcorona.github.io/words/recsys-challenge-part-i</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://recsys.acm.org/recsys15/&quot;&gt;RecSys’15&lt;/a&gt; is ready to roll! We have a date, a venue, a call for papers, and, of course, a challenge. Last November, the details for this year’s RecSys challenge were announced, and the leaderboards are already getting submissions (more info in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://recsys.acm.org/recsys15/challenge/&quot;&gt;RecSys’15 website&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;http://2015.recsyschallenge.com&quot;&gt;challenge website&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The german company &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.yoochoose.com/en/&quot;&gt;Yoochoose&lt;/a&gt;, which provides recommendations for e-commerce platforms, news and media, sponsors the competition. They give us a dataset of completely anonimized (unless otherwise proven) implicit feedback data coming from an e-commerce business located in Europe. The business sells all kind of stuff such as garden tools, toys, clothes, electronics and much more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;33 MILLION CLICKS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;strong&gt;1.1 MILLION BUYS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;strong&gt;9 MILLION SESSIONS (USERS)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;strong&gt;53K ITEMS&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The data represents six months worth of clicks grouped in sessions, from April 1st to September 30th. For some of the sessions (around 5%), there are also buying events, which is the interesting part, as the goal of this challenge is to predict whether the user (a session) is going to buy something or not, and if she is actually buying, what are the items bought. At this point it is important to note that user and sessions are equivalent in this problem. Since the data is anonymised, the terms session and users are interchangeable in this post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The problem can be defined in the following way: Given a sequence of click events (recorded in a user session on the e-commerce website)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Is the user going to buy items in this session?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If the user buys, what are the items that are going to be bought?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have already introduced the problem, now it is time to analyze the data. I will not go into detail about the data representation, as it is very well described in the competition website (&lt;a href=&quot;http://2015.recsyschallenge.com/challenge.html&quot;&gt;under challenge&lt;/a&gt;). The data is presented in two files, one for clicks and another one for buys. However, in this analysis I present the clicks and buy from the same session together, to get a better sense of the problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table class=&quot;MsoTableGrid&quot; style=&quot;border-collapse: collapse; border: none; mso-border-alt: solid windowtext .5pt; mso-yfti-tbllook: 1184; mso-padding-alt: 0cm 5.4pt 0cm 5.4pt;&quot; border=&quot;1&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot; cellpadding=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
  &lt;tr style=&quot;mso-yfti-irow: 0; mso-yfti-firstrow: yes;&quot;&gt;
    &lt;td style=&quot;width: 140.1pt; border: solid windowtext 1.0pt; mso-border-alt: solid windowtext .5pt; padding: 0cm 5.4pt 0cm 5.4pt;&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; width=&quot;140&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;margin-bottom: .0001pt; text-align: center; mso-pagination: none; tab-stops: 28.0pt 56.0pt 84.0pt 112.0pt 140.0pt 168.0pt 196.0pt 224.0pt 252.0pt 280.0pt 308.0pt 336.0pt; mso-layout-grid-align: none; text-autospace: none;&quot; align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
        &lt;b style=&quot;mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 11.0pt; font-family: Helvetica;&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;
      &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    
    &lt;td style=&quot;width: 70.85pt; border: solid windowtext 1.0pt; border-left: none; mso-border-left-alt: solid windowtext .5pt; mso-border-alt: solid windowtext .5pt; padding: 0cm 5.4pt 0cm 5.4pt;&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; width=&quot;71&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;margin-bottom: .0001pt; text-align: center; mso-pagination: none; tab-stops: 28.0pt 56.0pt 84.0pt 112.0pt 140.0pt 168.0pt 196.0pt 224.0pt 252.0pt 280.0pt 308.0pt 336.0pt; mso-layout-grid-align: none; text-autospace: none;&quot; align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
        &lt;b style=&quot;mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 11.0pt; font-family: Helvetica;&quot;&gt;AVERAGE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;
      &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    
    &lt;td style=&quot;width: 108.4pt; border: solid windowtext 1.0pt; border-left: none; mso-border-left-alt: solid windowtext .5pt; mso-border-alt: solid windowtext .5pt; padding: 0cm 5.4pt 0cm 5.4pt;&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; width=&quot;108&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;margin-bottom: .0001pt; text-align: center; mso-pagination: none; tab-stops: 28.0pt 56.0pt 84.0pt 112.0pt 140.0pt 168.0pt 196.0pt 224.0pt 252.0pt 280.0pt 308.0pt 336.0pt; mso-layout-grid-align: none; text-autospace: none;&quot; align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
        &lt;b style=&quot;mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 11.0pt; font-family: Helvetica;&quot;&gt;MEDIAN&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;
      &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    
    &lt;td style=&quot;width: 106.45pt; border: solid windowtext 1.0pt; border-left: none; mso-border-left-alt: solid windowtext .5pt; mso-border-alt: solid windowtext .5pt; padding: 0cm 5.4pt 0cm 5.4pt;&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; width=&quot;106&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;margin-bottom: .0001pt; text-align: center; mso-pagination: none; tab-stops: 28.0pt 56.0pt 84.0pt 112.0pt 140.0pt 168.0pt 196.0pt 224.0pt 252.0pt 280.0pt 308.0pt 336.0pt; mso-layout-grid-align: none; text-autospace: none;&quot; align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
        &lt;b style=&quot;mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 11.0pt; font-family: Helvetica;&quot;&gt;STD&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;
      &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  
  &lt;tr style=&quot;mso-yfti-irow: 1;&quot;&gt;
    &lt;td style=&quot;width: 140.1pt; border: solid windowtext 1.0pt; border-top: none; mso-border-top-alt: solid windowtext .5pt; mso-border-alt: solid windowtext .5pt; padding: 0cm 5.4pt 0cm 5.4pt;&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; width=&quot;140&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;margin-bottom: .0001pt; text-align: center; mso-pagination: none; tab-stops: 28.0pt 56.0pt 84.0pt 112.0pt 140.0pt 168.0pt 196.0pt 224.0pt 252.0pt 280.0pt 308.0pt 336.0pt; mso-layout-grid-align: none; text-autospace: none;&quot; align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
        &lt;b style=&quot;mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 11.0pt; font-family: Helvetica;&quot;&gt;SESSION LENGTH&lt;br /&gt; (EVENTS)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;
      &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    
    &lt;td style=&quot;width: 70.85pt; border-top: none; border-left: none; border-bottom: solid windowtext 1.0pt; border-right: solid windowtext 1.0pt; mso-border-top-alt: solid windowtext .5pt; mso-border-left-alt: solid windowtext .5pt; mso-border-alt: solid windowtext .5pt; padding: 0cm 5.4pt 0cm 5.4pt;&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; width=&quot;71&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;margin-bottom: .0001pt; text-align: center; mso-pagination: none; tab-stops: 28.0pt 56.0pt 84.0pt 112.0pt 140.0pt 168.0pt 196.0pt 224.0pt 252.0pt 280.0pt 308.0pt 336.0pt; mso-layout-grid-align: none; text-autospace: none;&quot; align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
        &lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 11.0pt; font-family: Helvetica;&quot;&gt;3.693&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    
    &lt;td style=&quot;width: 108.4pt; border-top: none; border-left: none; border-bottom: solid windowtext 1.0pt; border-right: solid windowtext 1.0pt; mso-border-top-alt: solid windowtext .5pt; mso-border-left-alt: solid windowtext .5pt; mso-border-alt: solid windowtext .5pt; padding: 0cm 5.4pt 0cm 5.4pt;&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; width=&quot;108&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;margin-bottom: .0001pt; text-align: center; mso-pagination: none; tab-stops: 28.0pt 56.0pt 84.0pt 112.0pt 140.0pt 168.0pt 196.0pt 224.0pt 252.0pt 280.0pt 308.0pt 336.0pt; mso-layout-grid-align: none; text-autospace: none;&quot; align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
        &lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 11.0pt; font-family: Helvetica;&quot;&gt;2.0&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    
    &lt;td style=&quot;width: 106.45pt; border-top: none; border-left: none; border-bottom: solid windowtext 1.0pt; border-right: solid windowtext 1.0pt; mso-border-top-alt: solid windowtext .5pt; mso-border-left-alt: solid windowtext .5pt; mso-border-alt: solid windowtext .5pt; padding: 0cm 5.4pt 0cm 5.4pt;&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; width=&quot;106&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;margin-bottom: .0001pt; text-align: center; mso-pagination: none; tab-stops: 28.0pt 56.0pt 84.0pt 112.0pt 140.0pt 168.0pt 196.0pt 224.0pt 252.0pt 280.0pt 308.0pt 336.0pt; mso-layout-grid-align: none; text-autospace: none;&quot; align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
        &lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 11.0pt; font-family: Helvetica;&quot;&gt;4.04&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;/p&gt;
      
      &lt;p class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;margin-bottom: .0001pt; text-align: center; mso-pagination: none; tab-stops: 28.0pt 56.0pt 84.0pt 112.0pt 140.0pt 168.0pt 196.0pt 224.0pt 252.0pt 280.0pt 308.0pt 336.0pt; mso-layout-grid-align: none; text-autospace: none;&quot; align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
        &lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 11.0pt; font-family: Helvetica;&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  
  &lt;tr style=&quot;mso-yfti-irow: 2;&quot;&gt;
    &lt;td style=&quot;width: 140.1pt; border: solid windowtext 1.0pt; border-top: none; mso-border-top-alt: solid windowtext .5pt; mso-border-alt: solid windowtext .5pt; padding: 0cm 5.4pt 0cm 5.4pt;&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; width=&quot;140&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;margin-bottom: .0001pt; text-align: center; mso-pagination: none; tab-stops: 28.0pt 56.0pt 84.0pt 112.0pt 140.0pt 168.0pt 196.0pt 224.0pt 252.0pt 280.0pt 308.0pt 336.0pt; mso-layout-grid-align: none; text-autospace: none;&quot; align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
        &lt;b style=&quot;mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 11.0pt; font-family: Helvetica;&quot;&gt;SESSSION LENGTH&lt;br /&gt; (&lt;strong&gt;EVENTS&lt;/strong&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;
      &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    
    &lt;td style=&quot;width: 70.85pt; border-top: none; border-left: none; border-bottom: solid windowtext 1.0pt; border-right: solid windowtext 1.0pt; mso-border-top-alt: solid windowtext .5pt; mso-border-left-alt: solid windowtext .5pt; mso-border-alt: solid windowtext .5pt; padding: 0cm 5.4pt 0cm 5.4pt;&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; width=&quot;71&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;margin-bottom: .0001pt; text-align: center; mso-pagination: none; tab-stops: 28.0pt 56.0pt 84.0pt 112.0pt 140.0pt 168.0pt 196.0pt 224.0pt 252.0pt 280.0pt 308.0pt 336.0pt; mso-layout-grid-align: none; text-autospace: none;&quot; align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
        &lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 11.0pt; font-family: Helvetica;&quot;&gt;404.428&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    
    &lt;td style=&quot;width: 108.4pt; border-top: none; border-left: none; border-bottom: solid windowtext 1.0pt; border-right: solid windowtext 1.0pt; mso-border-top-alt: solid windowtext .5pt; mso-border-left-alt: solid windowtext .5pt; mso-border-alt: solid windowtext .5pt; padding: 0cm 5.4pt 0cm 5.4pt;&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; width=&quot;108&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;margin-bottom: .0001pt; text-align: center; mso-pagination: none; tab-stops: 28.0pt 56.0pt 84.0pt 112.0pt 140.0pt 168.0pt 196.0pt 224.0pt 252.0pt 280.0pt 308.0pt 336.0pt; mso-layout-grid-align: none; text-autospace: none;&quot; align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
        &lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 11.0pt; font-family: Helvetica;&quot;&gt;134.0&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    
    &lt;td style=&quot;width: 106.45pt; border-top: none; border-left: none; border-bottom: solid windowtext 1.0pt; border-right: solid windowtext 1.0pt; mso-border-top-alt: solid windowtext .5pt; mso-border-left-alt: solid windowtext .5pt; mso-border-alt: solid windowtext .5pt; padding: 0cm 5.4pt 0cm 5.4pt;&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; width=&quot;106&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;margin-bottom: .0001pt; text-align: center; mso-pagination: none; tab-stops: 28.0pt 56.0pt 84.0pt 112.0pt 140.0pt 168.0pt 196.0pt 224.0pt 252.0pt 280.0pt 308.0pt 336.0pt; mso-layout-grid-align: none; text-autospace: none;&quot; align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
        &lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 11.0pt; font-family: Helvetica;&quot;&gt;782.123&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  
  &lt;tr style=&quot;mso-yfti-irow: 3;&quot;&gt;
    &lt;td style=&quot;width: 140.1pt; border: solid windowtext 1.0pt; border-top: none; mso-border-top-alt: solid windowtext .5pt; mso-border-alt: solid windowtext .5pt; padding: 0cm 5.4pt 0cm 5.4pt;&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; width=&quot;140&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;margin-bottom: .0001pt; text-align: center; mso-pagination: none; tab-stops: 28.0pt 56.0pt 84.0pt 112.0pt 140.0pt 168.0pt 196.0pt 224.0pt 252.0pt 280.0pt 308.0pt 336.0pt; mso-layout-grid-align: none; text-autospace: none;&quot; align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
        &lt;b style=&quot;mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 11.0pt; font-family: Helvetica;&quot;&gt;CLICKS PER ITEM&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;
      &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    
    &lt;td style=&quot;width: 70.85pt; border-top: none; border-left: none; border-bottom: solid windowtext 1.0pt; border-right: solid windowtext 1.0pt; mso-border-top-alt: solid windowtext .5pt; mso-border-left-alt: solid windowtext .5pt; mso-border-alt: solid windowtext .5pt; padding: 0cm 5.4pt 0cm 5.4pt;&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; width=&quot;71&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;margin-bottom: .0001pt; text-align: center; mso-pagination: none; tab-stops: 28.0pt 56.0pt 84.0pt 112.0pt 140.0pt 168.0pt 196.0pt 224.0pt 252.0pt 280.0pt 308.0pt 336.0pt; mso-layout-grid-align: none; text-autospace: none;&quot; align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
        &lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 11.0pt; font-family: Helvetica;&quot;&gt;625.79&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    
    &lt;td style=&quot;width: 108.4pt; border-top: none; border-left: none; border-bottom: solid windowtext 1.0pt; border-right: solid windowtext 1.0pt; mso-border-top-alt: solid windowtext .5pt; mso-border-left-alt: solid windowtext .5pt; mso-border-alt: solid windowtext .5pt; padding: 0cm 5.4pt 0cm 5.4pt;&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; width=&quot;108&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;margin-bottom: .0001pt; text-align: center; mso-pagination: none; tab-stops: 28.0pt 56.0pt 84.0pt 112.0pt 140.0pt 168.0pt 196.0pt 224.0pt 252.0pt 280.0pt 308.0pt 336.0pt; mso-layout-grid-align: none; text-autospace: none;&quot; align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
        &lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 11.0pt; font-family: Helvetica;&quot;&gt;22.0&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    
    &lt;td style=&quot;width: 106.45pt; border-top: none; border-left: none; border-bottom: solid windowtext 1.0pt; border-right: solid windowtext 1.0pt; mso-border-top-alt: solid windowtext .5pt; mso-border-left-alt: solid windowtext .5pt; mso-border-alt: solid windowtext .5pt; padding: 0cm 5.4pt 0cm 5.4pt;&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; width=&quot;106&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;margin-bottom: .0001pt; text-align: center; mso-pagination: none; tab-stops: 28.0pt 56.0pt 84.0pt 112.0pt 140.0pt 168.0pt 196.0pt 224.0pt 252.0pt 280.0pt 308.0pt 336.0pt; mso-layout-grid-align: none; text-autospace: none;&quot; align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
        &lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 11.0pt; font-family: Helvetica;&quot;&gt;2810.05&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  
  &lt;tr style=&quot;mso-yfti-irow: 4; mso-yfti-lastrow: yes;&quot;&gt;
    &lt;td style=&quot;width: 140.1pt; border: solid windowtext 1.0pt; border-top: none; mso-border-top-alt: solid windowtext .5pt; mso-border-alt: solid windowtext .5pt; padding: 0cm 5.4pt 0cm 5.4pt;&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; width=&quot;140&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;margin-bottom: .0001pt; text-align: center; mso-pagination: none; tab-stops: 28.0pt 56.0pt 84.0pt 112.0pt 140.0pt 168.0pt 196.0pt 224.0pt 252.0pt 280.0pt 308.0pt 336.0pt; mso-layout-grid-align: none; text-autospace: none;&quot; align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
        &lt;b style=&quot;mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 11.0pt; font-family: Helvetica;&quot;&gt;PURCHASES PER&lt;br /&gt; SESSION&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;
      &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    
    &lt;td style=&quot;width: 70.85pt; border-top: none; border-left: none; border-bottom: solid windowtext 1.0pt; border-right: solid windowtext 1.0pt; mso-border-top-alt: solid windowtext .5pt; mso-border-left-alt: solid windowtext .5pt; mso-border-alt: solid windowtext .5pt; padding: 0cm 5.4pt 0cm 5.4pt;&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; width=&quot;71&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;margin-bottom: .0001pt; text-align: center; mso-pagination: none; tab-stops: 28.0pt 56.0pt 84.0pt 112.0pt 140.0pt 168.0pt 196.0pt 224.0pt 252.0pt 280.0pt 308.0pt 336.0pt; mso-layout-grid-align: none; text-autospace: none;&quot; align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
        &lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 11.0pt; font-family: Helvetica;&quot;&gt;0.124&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    
    &lt;td style=&quot;width: 108.4pt; border-top: none; border-left: none; border-bottom: solid windowtext 1.0pt; border-right: solid windowtext 1.0pt; mso-border-top-alt: solid windowtext .5pt; mso-border-left-alt: solid windowtext .5pt; mso-border-alt: solid windowtext .5pt; padding: 0cm 5.4pt 0cm 5.4pt;&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; width=&quot;108&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;margin-bottom: .0001pt; text-align: center; mso-pagination: none; tab-stops: 28.0pt 56.0pt 84.0pt 112.0pt 140.0pt 168.0pt 196.0pt 224.0pt 252.0pt 280.0pt 308.0pt 336.0pt; mso-layout-grid-align: none; text-autospace: none;&quot; align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
        &lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 11.0pt; font-family: Helvetica;&quot;&gt;0.0&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    
    &lt;td style=&quot;width: 106.45pt; border-top: none; border-left: none; border-bottom: solid windowtext 1.0pt; border-right: solid windowtext 1.0pt; mso-border-top-alt: solid windowtext .5pt; mso-border-left-alt: solid windowtext .5pt; mso-border-alt: solid windowtext .5pt; padding: 0cm 5.4pt 0cm 5.4pt;&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; width=&quot;106&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;margin-bottom: .0001pt; text-align: center; mso-pagination: none; tab-stops: 28.0pt 56.0pt 84.0pt 112.0pt 140.0pt 168.0pt 196.0pt 224.0pt 252.0pt 280.0pt 308.0pt 336.0pt; mso-layout-grid-align: none; text-autospace: none;&quot; align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
        &lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 11.0pt; font-family: Helvetica;&quot;&gt;0.687&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;
  The table above shows a large deviation (from the mean) in the number of clicks that an item receives. We further investigate this by plotting the item popularity distribution in the figure below. This figure shows the distribution of clicks across items. The horizontal axis represents each of the items (plotted in a logarithmic scale), while the vertical axis represents the number of clicks that particular item received (also plotted in a logarithmic scale).
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;
  Thus, we have the classical scenario of the long tail, where a small subset of items get many clicks (they are very popular), while most of the items in the catalog get a very small number of clicks. In this dataset, 10% of the items (the 5200 most popular) get circa 90% of the clicks, while the remaining 90% of items only get 10% of the clicks.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_351&quot; style=&quot;width: 710px&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;http://aloneindecember.com/words/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/image001.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-large wp-image-351&quot; src=&quot;http://aloneindecember.com/words/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/image001-1024x796.png&quot; alt=&quot;figure 1 caption&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;544&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  
  &lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;
    Item popularity distribution
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now let’s move on to session length, in the first effort to understand all the aspects of a session, as it is our main information source. We can measure session length in terms of number of clicks or time duration (for example, in seconds).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the table above we know that the average session length is 2.69 clicks and lasts around 6.7 minutes (404.42 seconds). However, the deviation from the mean in both metrics is very large. Thus, we will find very short sessions and very long sessions, of up to 68 hours (session id:  10145339 ) and 261 clicks (session id: 6149111).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The figures below show the histogram of session lengths in time and clicks. The horizontal axis represents the length (seconds or clicks), while the vertical axis represents the number of sessions with that particular length in a logarithmic scale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the information in the graphs, we know that 51% of the sessions have less than three clicks. Thus, sessions tend to be short (90% of the sessions have less than 8 clicks), and there are only a  few longer sessions, of up to 200 clicks.  We see similar patterns in the case of session length distribution calculated by clicks. Something expected, as clicks and time must be  highly correlated (&lt;em&gt;humans can only click and browse at a certain speed, right?&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;a href=&quot;http://aloneindecember.com/words/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/Screen-Shot-2015-04-01-at-11.42.15.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter wp-image-484 size-large&quot; src=&quot;http://aloneindecember.com/words/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/Screen-Shot-2015-04-01-at-11.42.15-1024x828.png&quot; alt=&quot;Screen Shot 2015-04-01 at 11.42.15&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;566&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_353&quot; style=&quot;width: 710px&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-353 size-large&quot; src=&quot;http://aloneindecember.com/words/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/image003-1024x741.png&quot; alt=&quot;image003&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;507&quot; /&gt;
  
  &lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;
    Session length distribution (measured in time)
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, it is very interesting to know if the number of times a user clicks (or the time a user spends browsing) is correlated with a higher probability of purchasing an item (do not mistake for number of items bought, that is a different story!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a clear trend showing that longer sessions have, on average, more shopping transactions. However, this is true up to around 40 clicks, and after that the number of sessions available is very small. (We don’t have many sessions with more than 40 clicks – only around 10000 to be exact)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_357&quot; style=&quot;width: 710px&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-357 size-large&quot; src=&quot;http://aloneindecember.com/words/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/image007-1024x743.png&quot; alt=&quot;image007&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;508&quot; /&gt;
  
  &lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;
    Session length distribution
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a final note! When I wanted to analyse the prizes of items bought, we found out that around 53% of the transactions have no associated prize (or quantity of items bought). When doing some search to understand this, I saw the following message from @abellogin (picture below). It turns out that data is simply missing!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_359&quot; style=&quot;width: 427px&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-359 size-full&quot; src=&quot;http://aloneindecember.com/words/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/image010.png&quot; alt=&quot;image010&quot; width=&quot;417&quot; height=&quot;314&quot; /&gt;
  
  &lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;
    Something weird in the data &amp;#8230;
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://aloneindecember.com/words/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/image011.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-360&quot; src=&quot;http://aloneindecember.com/words/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/image011.png&quot; alt=&quot;image011&quot; width=&quot;565&quot; height=&quot;263&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hi, I am &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.insight-centre.org/users/humberto-corona&quot;&gt;Humberto Corona&lt;/a&gt; and I write this blog! Since October 2014, I am a PhD student at the Insight Centre for Data Analytics in UCD.  I would like to thank the members of the  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.insight-centre.org/about/team&quot;&gt;recommender systems team&lt;/a&gt; in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.insight-centre.org&quot;&gt;Insight Centre for Data Analytics&lt;/a&gt; for their discussions on this topic.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>A Weekend of Art in San Francisco</title>
   <link href="http://hcorona.github.io/words/a-weekend-of-art-in-san-francisco/"/>
   <updated>2014-12-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://hcorona.github.io/words/a-weekend-of-art-in-san-francisco</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Last October I spent 10 days in San Francisco, my friends at &lt;a href=&quot;http://theissuemagazine.com/san-francisco/&quot;&gt;THE ISSUE magazine&lt;/a&gt; were kind enough to publish my art review of a weekend in the city. Featuring the most interesting museums and the new exhibition @large from Ai Weiwei in Alcatraz, you can read it in their &lt;a href=&quot;http://theissuemagazine.com/san-francisco/&quot;&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_284&quot; style=&quot;width: 710px&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;http://aloneindecember.com/words/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/2014-10-09-18.19.38.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-284 size-large&quot; src=&quot;http://aloneindecember.com/words/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/2014-10-09-18.19.38-1024x575.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2014-10-09 18.19.38&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;393&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  
  &lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;
    Ai Weiwei @large
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_295&quot; style=&quot;width: 710px&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;http://aloneindecember.com/words/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/2014-10-05-15.09.29.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-295 size-large&quot; src=&quot;http://aloneindecember.com/words/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/2014-10-05-15.09.29-1024x575.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2014-10-05 15.09.29&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;393&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  
  &lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;
    Saigon, Minessota by Eric Fischl &amp;#8211; 1985
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_294&quot; style=&quot;width: 710px&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;http://aloneindecember.com/words/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/2014-10-05-15.12.48.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-294 size-large&quot; src=&quot;http://aloneindecember.com/words/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/2014-10-05-15.12.48-1024x575.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2014-10-05 15.12.48&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;393&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  
  &lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;
    Roy Lichenstein, Painting with Statue of Liberty, 1983
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_318&quot; style=&quot;width: 710px&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;http://aloneindecember.com/words/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/2014-10-05-16.20.14.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-318 size-large&quot; src=&quot;http://aloneindecember.com/words/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/2014-10-05-16.20.14-1024x183.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2014-10-05 16.20.14&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;125&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  
  &lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;
    Views from the Tower in Der Young are worth a go!
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Ryan McGinley, perpetua y dinámica juventud y belleza</title>
   <link href="http://hcorona.github.io/words/330/"/>
   <updated>2014-12-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://hcorona.github.io/words/330</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_331&quot; style=&quot;width: 660px&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;http://aloneindecember.com/words/wp-content/uploads/2014/12/Blue_Falling_2007_20x241.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-331 size-full&quot; src=&quot;http://aloneindecember.com/words/wp-content/uploads/2014/12/Blue_Falling_2007_20x241.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Blue_Falling_2007_20x241&quot; width=&quot;650&quot; height=&quot;436&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  
  &lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;
    Blue Falling (2007)
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Era invierno del 2008, yo vivía en Viena y pasaba infinitas horas en tumblr cuando un día vi por primera vez una fotografía de Ryan McGinley (Nueva Jersey, 1977,). Instantáneamente me sentí atraído por la belleza y juventud que desprende su trabajo y hasta hoy es mi fotógrafo favorito.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ryan McGinley creció entre New Jersey y Nueva York, donde vivía uno de sus hermanos. Enamorado de aquella ciudad se mudó tan pronto como pudo. Allí, su círculo de amistades era una mezcla entre la escena local del skate, el arte urbano y el mundo gay, que incluía a gente como el artista callejero Snow (Nueva York, 1981-2009) o Dan Cole (Nueva Jersey, 1971) ambos sujetos frecuentes de sus fotografías. En esa época, – mientras estudiaba diseño gráfico en Parsons – solía fotografiar de una forma documental y obsesiva todo lo que le rodeaba. El resultado fue un retrato de la subcultura juvenil neoyorkina de finales de los 90’s a la que pertenecía. El sexo, las drogas, las fiestas y la juventud fueron temas recurrentes en la primera etapa este joven hasta entonces desconocido. El resultado de estos años de trabajo se plasmó en su primer libro &lt;em&gt;The Kids are Allright&lt;/em&gt;, auto impreso y distribuido personalmente a gente influyente del mundo del arte en Nueva York. Se cuenta que para el libro hizo más de 3000 fotos que luego seleccionó.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;En 2003 se convirtió en el artista más joven en exponer en &lt;em&gt;el &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://whitney.org/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Withney Museum of American Art&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; y poco después España marcó su punto de partida en Europa, donde su primera exposición en solitario fue en el &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.musac.es/index.php?ref=9200&quot;&gt;MUSAC&lt;/a&gt; de León en 2005. Desde entonces ha hecho innumerables exposiciones en solitario, cuyas aperturas normalmente acaban siendo desalojadas por la policía por la enorme cantidad de gente que va a verlas!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_335&quot; style=&quot;width: 660px&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;http://aloneindecember.com/words/wp-content/uploads/2014/12/victor_2010.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-full wp-image-335&quot; src=&quot;http://aloneindecember.com/words/wp-content/uploads/2014/12/victor_2010.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Victor (2010)&quot; width=&quot;650&quot; height=&quot;434&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  
  &lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;
    Victor (2010)
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Su estilo evoca inocencia y frescura, su trabajo está íntimamente relacionado con su juventud, la libertad del desnudo, la naturaleza y la acción. A lo largo del tiempo ha fotografiado escenas muy diversas, desde las fotos instantáneas del principio de su carrera a sus desnudos actuales de estudio o portadas de discos (&lt;em&gt;Sigur Ross&lt;/em&gt;). También ha hecho foto reportajes como el de los Juegos Olímpicos de Invierno, en donde retrató el deporte de una forma espléndida, campañas publicitarias y últimamente ha experimentado con el &lt;a href=&quot;http://ryanmcginley.com/entrance_romance&quot;&gt;video&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Una de sus señas de identidad son sus fotografías de desnudos en lugares paradisíacos de la geografía estadounidense. Cada año pasa meses preparando un viaje en el que un grupo selecto de modelos recorre con él el país en un autobús parando en los sitios más remotos para ser fotografiados. Ha fotografiado jóvenes en cuevas (serie de la cual publicó el libro &lt;em&gt;Moonmilk&lt;/em&gt;), lagos, gente subida a árboles, dunas o ríos, siempre desnudos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_332&quot; style=&quot;width: 660px&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;http://aloneindecember.com/words/wp-content/uploads/2014/12/JakeShiningRock.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-full wp-image-332&quot; src=&quot;http://aloneindecember.com/words/wp-content/uploads/2014/12/JakeShiningRock.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Jake (Shinning Rock) , de la serie Moonmilk&quot; width=&quot;650&quot; height=&quot;432&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  
  &lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;
    Jake (Shinning Rock) , de la serie Moonmilk
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;El trabajo de McGinley tiene un aspecto de frescura que va siempre ligado a la juventud y belleza y si bien al principio de su carrera la espontaneidad era gran parte de su trabajo, en los últimos años su trabajo ha ido evolucionando claramente a producciones cada vez más grandes y elaboradas. Se ayuda de medios técnicos como fuegos artificiales, iluminación o trampolines, que junto a un proceso de postproducción en el que las imágenes son manipuladas hace que las escenas parezcan una mezcla entre la realidad que el artista ve y la que quiere transmitir para su trabajo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;dl id=&quot;attachment_334&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; style=&quot;width: 660px;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;dt class=&quot;wp-caption-dt&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div id=&quot;attachment_334&quot; style=&quot;width: 660px&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot;&gt;
      &lt;a href=&quot;http://aloneindecember.com/words/wp-content/uploads/2014/12/Shane-Foxtail-Barley.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-334 size-full&quot; src=&quot;http://aloneindecember.com/words/wp-content/uploads/2014/12/Shane-Foxtail-Barley.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;650&quot; height=&quot;433&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
      
      &lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;
        Shane (Foxtail Barley)
      &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ryan McGinely está representado por Team Gal (New York) y Allison Jackes Gallery (Londres). Ha publicado varios libros, entre ellos dos grandes retrospectivas de su trabajo. &lt;em&gt;You and I&lt;/em&gt; (Twin Palms Publishing,U.S. – 2006) y &lt;em&gt;A Whisthle for the Wind&lt;/em&gt; (Rizzoli International Publications, 2012).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Todas las imagenes por cortesía de Ryan McGinley y &lt;span class=&quot;il&quot;&gt;team&lt;/span&gt; (gallery, inc.), New York.&lt;br /&gt;
Este artículo apareció originalmente  publicado en la revista Temps de Vacances &lt;a href=&quot;http://issuu.com/tempsdevacances/docs/teps_de_vacances_n_1x/1#_=_&quot;&gt;(Issue #1)&lt;/a&gt;, 2014&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>black, gone.</title>
   <link href="http://hcorona.github.io/words/black-gone/"/>
   <updated>2014-09-27T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://hcorona.github.io/words/black-gone</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
  Your pictures are gone,&lt;br /&gt; and so is my love,&lt;br /&gt; my friendship, my willingness.&lt;br /&gt; And so are all my failed efforts to evolve.&lt;br /&gt; gone, gone, gone!
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
  The empty spaces are still there,&lt;br /&gt; they will never be filled,&lt;br /&gt; not with something else,&lt;br /&gt; not the same way,&lt;br /&gt; I don&amp;#8217;t care, I have lived, loved and learned.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
  The sorrow is gone, my memory flakes,&lt;br /&gt; soon this will be dead, buried in my head.&lt;br /&gt; I ain&amp;#8217;t wearing black.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;http://aloneindecember.com/words/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/Scan-23.jpeg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter wp-image-271 size-medium&quot; src=&quot;http://aloneindecember.com/words/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/Scan-23-244x300.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;void&quot; width=&quot;244&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>On what comes after us</title>
   <link href="http://hcorona.github.io/words/on-what-comes-after-us/"/>
   <updated>2014-07-30T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://hcorona.github.io/words/on-what-comes-after-us</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
    &lt;span style=&quot;line-height: 1.5em;&quot;&gt;Pictures of you are still hanging on the wall.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;line-height: 1.5em;&quot;&gt;I am not ready to change from lovers to whatever is next&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;line-height: 1.5em;&quot;&gt;Sometimes I miss you and sometimes I don&amp;#8217;t, all in the same day. &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
     I don&amp;#8217;t know what to say,&lt;br /&gt; &lt;span style=&quot;line-height: 1.5em;&quot;&gt;neither how to shut up&lt;br /&gt; and i &lt;/span&gt;definitely&lt;span style=&quot;line-height: 1.5em;&quot;&gt; don&amp;#8217;t want to hurt you.&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>On my inhibition when speaking</title>
   <link href="http://hcorona.github.io/words/on-my-inhibition-when-speaking/"/>
   <updated>2014-07-30T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://hcorona.github.io/words/on-my-inhibition-when-speaking</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
  There was  a time where we could speak clear.&lt;br /&gt; I used to tell you almost everything.&lt;br /&gt; Words would flow from my brain to my mouth without a filter,&lt;br /&gt; Now a big filter keeps me from even speaking,&lt;br /&gt; mainly because I loved you. Sometimes because I was sad, happy or angry.&lt;br /&gt; it is there to protect you, protect me, and because it has to be like this.
&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>On time</title>
   <link href="http://hcorona.github.io/words/on-time-and-space-ii/"/>
   <updated>2014-07-13T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://hcorona.github.io/words/on-time-and-space-ii</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
  From strangers to lust as fast as we could,&lt;br /&gt; from endless conversations to  unequivocal love,&lt;br /&gt; &lt;span style=&quot;line-height: 1.5em;&quot;&gt;from lovers to completing each other,&lt;br /&gt; from lust to imperative necessity, to &lt;/span&gt;routine&lt;span style=&quot;line-height: 1.5em;&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
  From lovers to strangers even faster,&lt;br /&gt; as if everything we lived had to be removed in order to live,&lt;br /&gt; from endless conversations to monosyllables,&lt;br /&gt; from lust do indifference, to being unknown,&lt;br /&gt; from completeness to the crude emptiness that evolves me.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
  From strangers to lovers and return, over and over again.&lt;br /&gt; Different faces telling the same stories,&lt;br /&gt; falling and failing in the pursue of an ephemeral happiness.&lt;br /&gt; I am not content.
&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>A weekend of art in London</title>
   <link href="http://hcorona.github.io/words/a-weekend-of-art-in-london/"/>
   <updated>2014-07-13T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://hcorona.github.io/words/a-weekend-of-art-in-london</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A day in London can start in countless ways. Mine started being woken up by a guy snoring in the bunk-bed next to mine on a cheap hostel near South Kensington; the perks of low budget accommodation! However, things turned on my side very soon when I left my bed, quickly dressed up and started exploring the streets of this beautiful neighbourhood where you find all the cool shops where you can’t afford buying anything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My initial idea was to head to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.simonleegallery.com/&quot;&gt;Simon Lee gallery&lt;/a&gt; to get a few of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://larryclark.com/&quot;&gt;Larry Clark&lt;/a&gt; photographs being sold for 100£ that week, in a similar fashion than the initial sale at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2014/01/09/arts/design/larry-clark-sells-snapshots-for-100-each.html&quot;&gt;home alone 2&lt;/a&gt; gallery in New York.  So  there I headed, browsed trough thousand of original 10″x6″ prints and selected one. Larry Clark, forever young at his 70s said &lt;em&gt;“This is a payback to all the skate rats and collectors who would like a souvenir, so I can die happy”. *Well Larry, i got one and I’m happy but this is far from a souvenir for me.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
*&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_237&quot; style=&quot;width: 710px&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;http://aloneindecember.com/words/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/2014-07-05-11.25.25.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-large wp-image-237&quot; alt=&quot;2014-07-05 11.25.25&quot; src=&quot;http://aloneindecember.com/words/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/2014-07-05-11.25.25-1024x575.jpg&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;393&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  
  &lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;
    The photographs were piled and presented in a box
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_234&quot; style=&quot;width: 710px&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;http://aloneindecember.com/words/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/2014-07-05-11.25.11.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-large wp-image-234&quot; alt=&quot;2014-07-05 11.25.11&quot; src=&quot;http://aloneindecember.com/words/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/2014-07-05-11.25.11-1024x575.jpg&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;393&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  
  &lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;
    The show attracted quite some people, not as many as the thousand of photographs
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Turns out the neighbourhood has a few other galleries (so the rich people who live in the area can buy art on the weekends) and I went to a few of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First I visited a really interesting small exhibition (from two huge artist) entitled “&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ordovasart.com/exhibitions/chillida-miro/images.html&quot;&gt;Chillida On Miró&lt;/a&gt;” at the ORDOVAS gallery. It was very interesting to see the collaboration of works produced by these two artists, who were good  friends and spent the summers of the 60s together with their families in France.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;width: 697px&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;http://aloneindecember.com/words/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/chillida-miro-slide-01.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;chillida-miro-slide-01&quot; src=&quot;http://aloneindecember.com/words/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/chillida-miro-slide-01.jpg&quot; width=&quot;687&quot; height=&quot;449&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  
  &lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;
    An overview of the exhibition courtesy of their website (as the gallery didn&amp;#8217;t allow me to take photos, thanks!)
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I headed to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://flemingcollection.com/&quot;&gt;Flemming Collection&lt;/a&gt;, where an exhibition about Sctotish photographer Petter Cattrell entitled &lt;a href=&quot;http://flemingcollection.com/traces-of-war-landscapes-of-the-western-front/&quot;&gt;“Traces of War”&lt;/a&gt; was showing. It was interesting, however I particularly liked a small section that was accompanying the main exhibition about women workers in Scotland during the first world war photographed by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nationalgalleries.org/collection/artists-a-z/l/artist/george-p-lewis&quot;&gt;George P Lewis&lt;/a&gt;. The photographs were commissioned for the imperial war museum in 1918 and show beautiful portrait of women working in the industry, a piece of history that is often overlooked. Very interesting to see if you are around!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just around the corner from the previous gallery, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hauserwirth.com/&quot;&gt;Hauser&amp;amp;Wirth&lt;/a&gt; had a really cool exhibition about the North American artist &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hauserwirth.com/artists/15/richard-jackson/biography/&quot;&gt;Richard Jackson&lt;/a&gt;. I hadn’t heard of him until then (yup, never ever), but I was positively surprised and it definetly captured my attention. His work, which combines painting, installation and sculpture is very visual and straightforward. I can’t say much about the work but rather show you a few of the snaps I took. The gallery was also showing some interesting drawing work by the British artist &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hauserwirth.com/artists/50/phyllida-barlow/biography/&quot;&gt;Phyllida Barlow&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_240&quot; style=&quot;width: 710px&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;http://aloneindecember.com/words/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/2014-07-05-12.01.19.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-large wp-image-240&quot; alt=&quot;2014-07-05 12.01.19&quot; src=&quot;http://aloneindecember.com/words/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/2014-07-05-12.01.19-1024x575.jpg&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;393&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  
  &lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;
    Paint-t, by Richard Jackson
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_241&quot; style=&quot;width: 585px&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;http://aloneindecember.com/words/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/2014-07-05-12.02.59.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-large wp-image-241&quot; alt=&quot;2014-07-05 12.02.59&quot; src=&quot;http://aloneindecember.com/words/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/2014-07-05-12.02.59-575x1024.jpg&quot; width=&quot;575&quot; height=&quot;1024&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  
  &lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;
    Copy Room, by Richard Jackson
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last and best for me, I attended the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.serpentinegalleries.org/exhibitions-events/marina-abramovic-512-hours&quot;&gt;512&lt;/a&gt; performance by &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Marina_Abramovi%C4%87&quot;&gt;Marina Abramovic&lt;/a&gt;. I t is  performance where for six days a week, eight hours a day Marina is performing her piece with 160 persons at a time. You are invited to come but you can leave whenever you want!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I say attend and not see it is because you don’t see it. Once you enter you are a vital part of the performance, as important as the artist herself. Having seen the documentary on her major retrospective artist in presence and some other small exhibitions in Madrid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I won’t explain the performance, which is held in the serpentine gallery until x august but rather explain what I experienced. First, the performance is carried out in total silence, and the visitor is welcomed to participate i na series of excersices which have been designed by the artist and her collaborators. It felt really good to be part of it, and at the same time I felt completely free and relaxed to do whatever I wanted to do withing the constrains given. A must if you are in London, and even better there were no queues!&lt;span style=&quot;line-height: 1.5em;&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_243&quot; style=&quot;width: 430px&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;http://aloneindecember.com/words/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/2014-07-10-14.04.46.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot; wp-image-243&quot; alt=&quot;2014-07-10 14.04.46&quot; src=&quot;http://aloneindecember.com/words/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/2014-07-10-14.04.46-768x1024.jpg&quot; width=&quot;420&quot; height=&quot;560&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  
  &lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;
    The only thing you will see of the exhibition until you actually get to go
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yeah, I also visited the TATE modern and liked their exhibition about &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tate.org.uk/art/artworks?sid=3501&quot;&gt;structure and clarity&lt;/a&gt; which shows some interesting minimalist works that I saw in 20 minutes as they were kicking me out. It would be nice that museums opened for longer in London, but now I have a good excuse to go back.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>On length, time and space</title>
   <link href="http://hcorona.github.io/words/215/"/>
   <updated>2014-05-16T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://hcorona.github.io/words/215</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
  Nothing is infinite.&lt;br /&gt; Not the Sea, not the Sun.&lt;br /&gt; Not the soil we stand on.&lt;br /&gt; Not the life, not the laugh,&lt;br /&gt; Not your smile.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
  Not even our sorrow is infinite.&lt;br /&gt; Not our happiness.&lt;br /&gt; Not the truth or the lies,&lt;br /&gt; nor the death.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
  Not the love or the hate,&lt;br /&gt; not me and you.&lt;br /&gt; Not this.
&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Patrick Scott: Image Space Light at IMMA</title>
   <link href="http://hcorona.github.io/words/patrick-scott-image-space-light-at-imma/"/>
   <updated>2014-03-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://hcorona.github.io/words/patrick-scott-image-space-light-at-imma</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago I went to the [IMMA][1] to see their new exhibition. A retrospective about the irish painter and architect [Patrick Scott][2].  I admit this is my favourite exhibition at the museum so far, and I am lucky because I discovered an irish gem, an unknown artist for me which surprised me greatly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The exhibition is not held in IMMAs newly renovated main building, but in the small house next to it. It is organised in three different floors and the exhibitions flows from Scott’s early career, where most of the word is commissioned for advertisement and textile prints, to a few different periods ending with his latest work, with the very define aesthetics he is associated with; gold over a tempura background using different geometric constructions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He had a prolific career: he exhibit in the MoMa in New York, won the Guggenheim Award in 1960, represented Ireland in the 1960 Venice Biennale and participated in the construction of one Irelands most famous buildings, the [Busáras bus station][3]. Patrick Scott passed away two day before his opening at the age of 93,  yet he lives through his work, like a few other lucky ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter&quot; alt=&quot;a001968645-001&quot; src=&quot;http://aloneindecember.com/words/wp-content/uploads/2014/03/a001968645-001.jpg&quot; width=&quot;423&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; /&gt;][4]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-202&quot; alt=&quot;gold-painting-7-90-patrick-scott&quot; src=&quot;http://aloneindecember.com/words/wp-content/uploads/2014/03/gold-painting-7-90-patrick-scott.jpg&quot; width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;474&quot; /&gt;][5]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;

 [1]: http://www.imma.ie/en/page_236799.htm
 [2]: http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Patrick_Scott
 [3]: http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bus%C3%A1ras
 [4]: http://aloneindecember.com/words/wp-content/uploads/2014/03/a001968645-001.jpg
 [5]: http://aloneindecember.com/words/wp-content/uploads/2014/03/gold-painting-7-90-patrick-scott.jpg
&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>haus tugendhat</title>
   <link href="http://hcorona.github.io/words/haus-tugendhat/"/>
   <updated>2014-02-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://hcorona.github.io/words/haus-tugendhat</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;If I had to describe beauty, it would not be far away from [Mies van der Rohe][1], since I visited the [Barcelona pavilion][2] and became aware of his legacy, I have been fascinated. Almost every decent office business in the world has a [Barcelona chair][3], a timeless piece originally designed in 1929.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once of Mies’ first commissions was the [Villa Tugendhat][4], a small villa designed for the daughter of a wealthy textile family in Brno. The house could easily have been designed this year, its pure lines and technical constructions methods are perfect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But in fact, I’d like to talk about the documentary “[Haus Tugendhat][5]“, which I saw in the Jameson international Film Festival. After this saturday’s projection, this villa means something else to me. A mix of History, life, family, joy, but also prosecution or spoilage …&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The documentary Haus Tugendhat (directed by [Dieter Reifarth][6]) research the life behind this precious architectural piece of the XX century. From their first inhabitants, the Tugendhat family, which had to run away from the nazi prosecution, to the patients recovering there from spinal injuries as childrens in the comunist checoslovaquia, I saw the house as a history more than a simple place. There was a connection between the people and the haus tugendhat, it made me realize how people connect to the places where they live, and they associate memories to them. Yet most of the people who lived in the house was unaware of its architecturally importance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[&lt;img alt=&quot;HausTugendhat&quot; src=&quot;http://aloneindecember.com/words/wp-content/uploads/2014/02/HausTugendhat.jpg&quot; width=&quot;1017&quot; height=&quot;644&quot; /&gt;][7]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An interesting topic which was discussed in the movie is the current state of the haus tugendhat. After years of deterioration and (part) of the Tugendhat family trying to recover it, now the house has been restored to its original state, mock-up furniture replaced the originals designed by Mies and Lilly Reich (some pieces specifically designed for the villa are still in production) and it is part of the [unesco world heritage][8], yet it feels that the house has lost more than 50 years of history in the process. All the marks, stories and changes made by its inhabitants are now lost, and it is reduced to a huge doll house for us to be seen but not touched.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-182&quot; alt=&quot;be31b25d0227883b_2493-w660-h330-b0-p0--modern-exterior&quot; src=&quot;http://aloneindecember.com/words/wp-content/uploads/2014/02/be31b25d0227883b_2493-w660-h330-b0-p0-modern-exterior.jpg&quot; width=&quot;660&quot; height=&quot;330&quot; /&gt;][9]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were lucky to have Michael Guggenheim (grandson of the original inhabitants and comissioners) as a guest for a Q&amp;amp;A session. I asked him what was the family’s opinion on the current state of the house, to what he answerded me that as in every family, there were different points of view. Thus, its only living original inhabitant, the philosopher Ernst Tugendhadt said he just doesn’t care. I somehow understood a position of a man whom as a kid lived in a house which was way ahead of its time, had to run away from the nazi prosecution and ended up living in many different countries and houses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d love to say more about the house, or the movie. But once the introductions have been made, I rather have you exploring by yourself than be guided into my biased views.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;centre&gt;  
&lt;span class=&quot;embed-youtube&quot; style=&quot;text-align:center; display: block;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;

 [1]: http://www.miessociety.org/
 [2]: http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Barcelona_Pavilion
 [3]: http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Barcelona_chair
 [4]: http://www.tugendhat.eu/en/villa-tugendhat/the-building.html
 [5]: www.jdiff.com/index.php/festival-2014/movie/haus_tugendhat
 [6]: http://www.imdb.com/name/nm0717545/
 [7]: http://aloneindecember.com/words/wp-content/uploads/2014/02/HausTugendhat.jpg
 [8]: http://whc.unesco.org/en/list/1052
 [9]: http://aloneindecember.com/words/wp-content/uploads/2014/02/be31b25d0227883b_2493-w660-h330-b0-p0-modern-exterior.jpg
&lt;/centre&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>some movies about artits I saw in 2013 : the Painter</title>
   <link href="http://hcorona.github.io/words/some-movies-about-artits-i-saw-in-2013-the-painter/"/>
   <updated>2014-01-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://hcorona.github.io/words/some-movies-about-artits-i-saw-in-2013-the-painter</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I know very little before watching &lt;a href=&quot;http://basquiat.com/&quot;&gt;Jean Michael Basquiat&lt;/a&gt; (1960 – 1988) before watching “&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0115632/?ref_=fn_al_tt_1&quot;&gt;Basquiat&lt;/a&gt;“, the movie about the meteoric rise (and fall) of this american painter. Now that I am writing about him and the movie, I still know very little about him and his work, but I am fascinated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_162&quot; style=&quot;width: 810px&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;http://aloneindecember.com/words/wp-content/uploads/2014/01/basquiat1.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-full wp-image-162&quot; alt=&quot;COVER_NYT_ORG&quot; src=&quot;http://aloneindecember.com/words/wp-content/uploads/2014/01/basquiat1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;813&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  
  &lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;
    New Art, New Money: The Marketing of an American Artist
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;
  Starting with empty hands, living in the streets or friends houses, this multifaceted artist became a major success, appearing in the New York Times magazine cover entitled &amp;#8220;New Art, New Money: The Marketing of an American Artist&amp;#8221;. He did graffiti with his friend Al Diaz under the name SAMO, he had a few bands and used to sell postcards to make a living before hitting the galleries, exhibiting his work all over the world.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The movie is (as far as I can tell) quite an accurate vision of his life, shows how this ambitious and yet naive man made it, enjoyed it and then fell into addiction, shortly after his friend Andy Warhol died. It shows how the art business was ran back then, changing galleries, ascend positions in the social-artist scale while making some people happy and some sad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;line-height: 1.5em;&quot;&gt;There is very little left to say from be about this great artist, I can only recommend you watch his movie and start researching his work as I have been doing in the past weeks.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>some movies about artists I saw in 2013 : the architects list</title>
   <link href="http://hcorona.github.io/words/some-movies-about-artists-i-saw-in-2013-the-architects-list/"/>
   <updated>2014-01-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://hcorona.github.io/words/some-movies-about-artists-i-saw-in-2013-the-architects-list</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_145&quot; style=&quot;width: 730px&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;http://aloneindecember.com/words/wp-content/uploads/2014/01/eames.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot; wp-image-145 &quot; alt=&quot;eames&quot; src=&quot;http://aloneindecember.com/words/wp-content/uploads/2014/01/eames.jpg&quot; width=&quot;720&quot; height=&quot;466&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  
  &lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;
    Eames: The Architect &amp;amp; The Painter (2011)
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1972646/?ref_=nv_sr_1&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Eames : The Architect &amp;amp; the painter&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/a&gt; is one of the best movies about artists I saw last year, it documents very well the work and life of one of the most iconic industrial designers of the 20th century, and it portraits  how important the role of &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ray_Eames&quot;&gt;Ray Eames&lt;/a&gt; was in the whole creative process of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://eamesoffice.com/&quot;&gt;Eames office&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eames was a  couple of &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Modernism&quot;&gt;modernist&lt;/a&gt; artist who is most known for being the creator of some of the most popular chairs in the 20th century like the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vitra.com/en-gb/product/lounge-chair&quot;&gt;Ottoman Lounge chair&lt;/a&gt; (1956) or the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vitra.com/en-gb/product/eames-plastic-side-chair&quot;&gt;DSW plastic chair&lt;/a&gt; (1950), mid century pieces that we can still see nowadays everywhere from homes, offices or restaurants. The vision of the studio was to bring good design to the masses, and they delivered it in form of furniture, photography, &lt;a href=&quot;http://eamesoffice.com/film/&quot;&gt;film&lt;/a&gt;, or even toys like the &lt;a href=&quot;http://eamesoffice.com/toys/&quot;&gt;house of cards&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_149&quot; style=&quot;width: 610px&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;http://aloneindecember.com/words/wp-content/uploads/2014/01/rotatephp3.jpeg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-full wp-image-149 &quot; title=&quot;Visual Acoustics (2008)&quot; alt=&quot;visual acoustics&quot; src=&quot;http://aloneindecember.com/words/wp-content/uploads/2014/01/rotatephp3.jpeg&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  
  &lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;
    Visual Acoustics (2008)
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1233611/plotsummary?ref_=tt_ov_pl&quot;&gt;Visual Acoustics&lt;/a&gt;: the modernism of &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Julius_Shulman&quot;&gt;Julius Schulman&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; is a documentary film about the life of one of the most importan architectural photographers of the modernism movement. He photographed the most important architects while he lived: iconic structures from Frank Lloyd Wright, Richard Neutra, John Lautner, Frank Gehry or Eames, and he did it in a way that he brought modern architecture to the mainstream public.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Julius Schulman (1910 – 2009)  is one of the best architectural photographers that lived, and thru the film you get a sense of how important his work was to him and how passionate he was about it, up to the point that he stoped taking pictures (for a while) after once the&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Postmodern_architecture&quot;&gt; post-modernism&lt;/a&gt; movement started. His work is now preserved in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.getty.edu/research/tools/guides_bibliographies/shulman/&quot;&gt;getty  foundation&lt;/a&gt; and he lived to see his work published by the well known art publishers &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.taschen.com/pages/en/catalogue/architecture/all/04404/facts.julius_shulman_modernism_rediscovered.htm&quot;&gt;taschen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_151&quot; style=&quot;width: 810px&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;http://aloneindecember.com/words/wp-content/uploads/2014/01/how-much-does-your-building-weigh-mr.foster-1-2254.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-full wp-image-151&quot; alt=&quot;norman-foster&quot; src=&quot;http://aloneindecember.com/words/wp-content/uploads/2014/01/how-much-does-your-building-weigh-mr.foster-1-2254.jpg&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;450&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  
  &lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;
    How Much Does Your Building Weights, Mr. Foster? (2010)
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How Much Does My Building Weights, Mr Foster? Is the documentary  that narrates the career of one of the most prominent architect nowadays. The film, produced by Elena Ochoa (who run, among many other things &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ivorypress.com/&quot;&gt;IvoryPress&lt;/a&gt;, one of my favourite galleries in Madrid and also an editorial) portraits the result of a man’s hard work and passion for architecture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://simple.wikipedia.org/wiki/Norman_Foster_(architect)&quot;&gt;Lord Norman Foster&lt;/a&gt; has a curriculum lists an endless number of buildings and prizes acomplished with his architectural studio &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fosterandpartners.com/&quot;&gt;Foster&amp;amp;Partner&lt;/a&gt;s.  He restored the &lt;a href=&quot;http://simple.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reichstag&quot;&gt;Reichstag&lt;/a&gt; building in Berlin, designed  airports in Zagreb, Beijing, Hong Kong and London, or the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fosterandpartners.com/projects/torre-caja-madrid-tower/&quot;&gt;Torre Caja Madrid&lt;/a&gt; in Spain, and yet the film shows a familiar and ordinary man who is not extremely interesting in his daily basis life (or at least that’s the image the film portraits).&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>the issue magazine</title>
   <link href="http://hcorona.github.io/words/the-issue-magazine/"/>
   <updated>2012-02-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://hcorona.github.io/words/the-issue-magazine</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center;&quot;&gt;
  La semana pasada estuve en la exposición Presenza Activa en el museo de arte contemporaneo (MARCO) de Vigo y colaboré en un artículo para la revista The Issue Magazine, puedes leer el artículo en en su página web!
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter&quot; src=&quot;http://theissuemagazine.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/02/MARCO_FOTO5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;461&quot; height=&quot;346&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;http://theissuemagazine.com/?p=446&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;theissuemagazine.com &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Dallas Green, City and Colour</title>
   <link href="http://hcorona.github.io/words/dallas-green-city-and-colour/"/>
   <updated>2012-02-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://hcorona.github.io/words/dallas-green-city-and-colour</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Puedo decir sin miedo a ser juzgado que Dallas Green es un genio de la música. Después de pasar  diez años  con &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theonlybandever.com/&quot;&gt;Alexisonfire&lt;/a&gt;, en 2011 decidió que City and Colour – hasta entonces su proyecto paralelo –  tenía que ser el eje principal de su carrera y el resultado ha sido increíble,  un disco titulado &lt;em&gt;Little Hell&lt;/em&gt; que muestra una clara evolución de su estilo y una gira que lo ha llevado por EEUU, Canadá (su país de origen) y toda Europa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;http://cityandcolour.ca&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-full wp-image-116 aligncenter&quot; title=&quot;city and colour at the royal albert hall&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://aloneindecember.com/words/wp-content/uploads/2012/02/city_colour_royal_albert_hall_25_04_11_web-2975.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;333&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dallas Green en el Royal Albert Hall, Londes&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Todo empezó con la intención de grabar algunas canciones en las que Dallas había estado trabajando desde hacía mucho tiempo, su primer trabajo,titulado &lt;em&gt;Sometimes,&lt;/em&gt; fue una recopilación de algunos temas que habían sido compuestos desde que tenía 18, el resultado fue  muy personal y un tanto melancólico en cuanto a  sonido (guitarra acústica y  su voz melódica) y a la temática.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;En 2008 con &lt;em&gt;Bring me your love&lt;/em&gt; el sonido evolucionó ligeramente. Si bien seguía siendo un álbum acústico, su estilo era mucho mas maduro y la temática cambió a medida que Dallas Green crecía … en 2011 &lt;em&gt;Little Hell&lt;/em&gt; se convirtió en uno de mis albums favoritos&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
  http://cityandcolour.ca/
&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>McGinley, Ryan.</title>
   <link href="http://hcorona.github.io/words/mcginley-ryan/"/>
   <updated>2012-02-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://hcorona.github.io/words/mcginley-ryan</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center;&quot;&gt;
  Ryan McGinley (1977, Nueva Jersey) es probablemente mi fotógrafo favorito, sus trabajos desprenden una energía, naturalidad y captan la juventud y frescura de forma que rara vez se ve y además es un fotógrafo muy joven que aún tiene mucho que ofrecernos.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;http://the-talks.com/interviews/ryan-mcginley/&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-medium wp-image-88&quot; style=&quot;border:1px solid black;&quot; title=&quot;ryan1&quot; src=&quot;http://aloneindecember.com/words/wp-content/uploads/2012/02/ryan1.jpg?w=300&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;199&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lleva desde los 21 haciendo fotografía en Nueva York y se comenta que para su primer libro, &lt;em&gt;the kids are alright&lt;/em&gt; (que imprimió él y  distribuyó a artistas de NY) hizo más de 3000 fotos que luego seleccionó.  En 2000 expuso en el &lt;a href=&quot;http://whitney.org/&quot;&gt;Withney Museum of American Art&lt;/a&gt; y desde entonces ha expuesto en casi todas partes, en España expuso en el &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.musac.es/index.php?ref=9200&quot;&gt;MUSAC&lt;/a&gt; de León en 2005 .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Su estilo evoca inocencia y frescura, su trabajo está íntimamente relacionado con su juventud, con el skate, con la escena fiestera-cultural, los graffities y todo lo que era  la escena independiente cultural del NY de los  90s. A lo largo del tiempo ha fotografiado escenas muy diversas, desde las fotos instantáneas del principio de su carrera a sus desnudos actuales e incluso hizo una gira por toda la geografía de EEUU en donde convivió con sus modelos durante 9 meses, el resultado son fotografías que recuerdan las mejores vacaciones que hayas podido pasar …&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;También ha hecho reportajes como el  de los juegos olímpicos de invierno en 2010  –&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ryanmcginley.com/wintergames&quot;&gt; winter olympics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, donde retrató el deporte de una forma espléndida – y campañas publicitarias, publicaciones en el NY Times, y últimamente ha experimentado con el &lt;a href=&quot;http://ryanmcginley.com/entrance_romance&quot;&gt;video&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;http://aloneindecember.com/words/wp-content/uploads/2012/02/tom_golden_tunnel.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-85&quot; title=&quot;Tom_Golden_Tunnel&quot; src=&quot;http://aloneindecember.com/words/wp-content/uploads/2012/02/tom_golden_tunnel.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;333&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Tom (Golden Tunnel)
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;http://aloneindecember.com/words/wp-content/uploads/2012/02/india_coyote.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-84&quot; title=&quot;India_(Coyote)&quot; src=&quot;http://aloneindecember.com/words/wp-content/uploads/2012/02/india_coyote.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;434&quot; height=&quot;650&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;India (Coyote), 2010 de &lt;em&gt;Life Adjustment Centre&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center;&quot;&gt;
  Tengo dos de los cinco libros y son de las mejores compras &amp;#8211; &lt;a href=&quot;http://http://www.dashwoodbooks.com/info.cfm?object_id=8182&amp;amp;inventory_id=8593&amp;amp;cookie1=262850.071825&amp;amp;email=&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Moonmilk&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211; y regalos  &amp;#8211; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dashwoodbooks.com/info.cfm?object_id=9146&amp;amp;inventory_id=9575&amp;amp;cookie1=262850.071825&amp;amp;email=&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Life Adjustment Center&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211;  que he tenido. Puedes visitar su web personal en donde hay una gran selección de contenido.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;http://ryanmcginley.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; http://ryanmcginley.com&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>fixed gear video teaser</title>
   <link href="http://hcorona.github.io/words/fixed-gear-video-teaser/"/>
   <updated>2012-01-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://hcorona.github.io/words/fixed-gear-video-teaser</id>
   <content type="html">
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Polaroid, ?</title>
   <link href="http://hcorona.github.io/words/instant-digital-no-thanks/"/>
   <updated>2012-01-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://hcorona.github.io/words/instant-digital-no-thanks</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;En 1948 &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Edwin_H._Land&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Edwin Land&lt;/a&gt; lanzaba su primera cámara instantánea en la empresa “&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Polaroid_Corporation&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;polaroid corporation&lt;/a&gt;” , esta y muchas otras fueron un éxito, pero en 2001 la polaroid corporation se declaró en bancarrota. En parte la mala gestión (Mr. Land murió en 1991) , y en parte la evolución del mercado empujado por la fotografía digital llevaron a que la compañía fuese comprada por otra que siguió usando tanto el nombre comercial como el corporativo. En 2008 se dejaron de vender cámaras polaroid (después de una nueva bancarrota) y en 2009 se dejó de vender el film. La nueva empresa que comercializa &lt;a href=&quot;http://polaroid.com/es/stream&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;POLAROID&lt;/a&gt; poco tiene que ver con la compañía original – y sus productos (que han sido desastre tras desastre) lo demuestran!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Son muchos los ejemplos, pero el último lanzamiento, su cámara &lt;a href=&quot;http://store.polaroid.com/product/9/356223/Z340/_/Z340_Instant_Digital_C%20amera&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Z340&lt;/a&gt; (a la izquierda en la foto) con tecnología digital zink  recuerda mas a un instrumento propio de star-trek que a una cámara instantánea como es la one-600 (a la derecha en la foto)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://aloneindecember.com/words/wp-content/uploads/2012/01/l_120632021.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-17&quot; title=&quot;polaroid-evolution&quot; src=&quot;http://aloneindecember.com/words/wp-content/uploads/2012/01/l_120632021.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;223&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;¿Qué camino ha seguido Polaroid? Sacar al mercado una cámara de 14megapixeles que sólo tiene una autonomía para imprimir 25 fotografías y cada fotografía tarda 45” en ser impresa resta toda la emoción y sensación de apego a la fotografía instantánea que se había producido con sus  modelo analógicos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://the-impossible-project.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;the-impossible-project&lt;/a&gt; lleva produciendo y vendiendo film para las verdaderas cámaras polaroid desde 2009. Presentan productos con un cuidado por los detalles impresionante, calidades de presentación geniales, colaboraciones con artistas que le dan exclusividad a sus productos lanzando series limitadas, y sobretodo han sabido mantener el espíritu de este tipo de fotografía haciéndola rentable sin tener que recurrir a productos excesivamente innovadores y complejos que la gente no entiende.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Creo que polaroid debería de asociarse con the-impossible-project, pedirle consejos sobre cómo hacer las cosas y sacar aquella cámara compatible con el film de the-impossible-project que se prometía para 2010 pero nunca llegó a ver la luz. En vez de contratar a Lady Gaga como directora creativa para lanzar productos de otras marcas (porque la &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.polaroid.com/en/products/classic-instant/polaroid-300-classic-instant-camera&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;polaroid300&lt;/a&gt; no es mas que una &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fujifilm.com/products/instant_photo/cameras/instax_mini_7/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;fuji instax mini&lt;/a&gt;) deberían de producir una línea mas cuidada y exclusiva que refleje lo que fue la compañía.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;La polaroid corporation original logró reunir una colección de fotografías magnífica, y logró hacer confluir la ciencia con el arte de forma extraordinaria, cautivando a artistas como &lt;a href=&quot;http://latimesblogs.latimes.com/culturemonster/2009/03/warhol-and-his.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Andy Warhol&lt;/a&gt;. Ahora la mayoría de estas fotografías han sido subastadas (para sanar la economía de las sucesivas empresas que han utilizado el nombre de polaroid) y se ha perdido todo el contacto con el arte que fue tan importante para el éxito de la polaroid original …. Bueno, a polaroid todavía le queda Lady Gaga no?&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
